The following content is provided
提供以下内容
under a Creative Commons license.
根据知识共享许可。
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare continue
您的支持将帮助MIT OpenCourseWare继续
to offer high quality educational resources for free.
免费提供高质量的教育资源。
To make a donation or view additional materials
捐款或查看其他材料
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
从数百门麻省理工学院的课程中，访问MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
在ocw.mit.edu。
VICTOR COSTAN: So I'm excited about today's recitation,
维克多·科斯坦：我对今天的朗诵感到很兴奋，
because if I do this right and you guys get it,
因为如果我做对了，你们明白了，
then I can mess up every other recitation after it.
然后我就可以搞乱所有其他的背诵。
And you'll still get the gist of 6.006.
而且您仍然会得到6.006的要旨。
So all I have to do is get this working.
所以我要做的就是使它工作。
So most of the time in the real world
因此，在现实世界中，大部分时间
you're probably not going to be coming up with new algorithms
您可能不会提出新算法
to do something, but rather you'll have some code
去做点事，但是你会有一些代码
and you want to make it faster.
而您想使其更快。
And the first step in making it faster
加快速度的第一步
is you realize, how does it do right now?
您知道吗，现在如何执行？
How does it run, which lines are slow, which lines are fast,
它是如何运行的，哪些行较慢，哪些行较快，
and where you can make improvements.
以及可以进行改进的地方。
So in lecture we talked about the Python Cost Model
因此，在讲座中，我们谈到了Python成本模型
which is what you use to look at the code
这是您用来查看代码的内容
and figure out how much time it takes to run.
并计算出需要多少时间。
And we talked about document distance,
我们谈到了文档距离，
which is a problem that we'll use
这是我们将要使用的问题
to practice our analysis skills.
练习我们的分析技能。
And this entire recitation is all
这整个背诵就是全部
about looking at versions of document distance
关于查看文档距离的版本
and analyzing them.
并分析它们。
So that's what we'll do, look at Python code,
这就是我们要做的，看一下Python代码，
look at Python code, look at Python code.
看一下Python代码，看一下Python代码。
So you better have handouts, because I can't project.
所以你最好有讲义，因为我不能投影。
OK, how many people remember the document distance problem?
好，有多少人记得文档距离问题？
You guys said you went to lecture, right?
你们说你去听课了吧？
OK, so very, very fast, document distance.
好的，非常非常快的文档距离。
I have two documents.
我有两个文件。
The fox is in the hat.
狐狸在帽子里。
And the fox is outside.
狐狸在外面。
Document 1, document 2.
文件1，文件2。
What's the first thing I want to do?
我想做的第一件事是什么？
So there are three operations that Eric mentioned in lecture.
因此，Eric在演讲中提到了三个操作。
Operation one, take each document,
操作一，取每个文件，
break it up into words.
把它分解成文字。
Right?
对？
This is a string.
这是一个字符串。
When I read it, then it becomes word one, word two, word three,
当我阅读它时，它就变成了第一，第二，第三单词，
word four, so on and so forth.
第四个字，依此类推。
Operation two, build document vectors
操作二，建立文档向量
out of the two documents.
在两个文件中。
So the documents are D1 and D2.
因此文档是D1和D2。
A document vector is basically a list
文档向量基本上是一个列表
of the words in the documents with a count of how many times
文档中单词的数量，计数多少次
each word appears in the document.
每个单词都出现在文档中。
So let's build a document vector for document one.
因此，让我们为一个文档建立一个文档向量。
I'm not going to write it formally,
我不会正式写
so can anyone tell me what it should look like,
所以谁能告诉我它的外观，
and I'll sort of write it down as a list.
我会把它写成一个列表。
So for all the words here, I want to list the words
所以对于这里的所有单词，我想列出这些单词
and how many times they show up.
以及他们出现了多少次。
Somebody, please.
拜托
AUDIENCE: The is in there twice?
听众：里面有两次？
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
The, twice.
两次。
AUDIENCE: Fox, once.
听众：狐狸，一次。
VICTOR COSTAN: One.
维克多·科斯坦：一。
AUDIENCE: Is, once.
听众：是一次。
VICTOR COSTAN: Is, one.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] in once.
听众：[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: In, one.
维克多·科斯坦：在其中之一。
AUDIENCE: Hat once.
听众：戴一次帽子。
VICTOR COSTAN: Awesome.
维克多·科斯坦：太棒了。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢你。
Second one.
第二个。
Another volunteer.
另一个志愿者
Yes, go for it.
是的，去吧。
AUDIENCE: The, once.
听众：一次。
VICTOR COSTAN: The, one.
维克多·波士坦：一个。
AUDIENCE: Fox, once.
听众：狐狸，一次。
VICTOR COSTAN: Fox, one
维克多·科斯坦：福克斯，一位
AUDIENCE: Is, one.
听众：是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: Is, one.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
AUDIENCE: Outside, one.
听众：在外面，一个。
VICTOR COSTAN: Outside, one.
维克多·科斯坦：外面，一个。
OK, so this is a document vector.
好的，这是文档向量。
Notice two small details.
请注意两个小细节。
Here, they is capitalized, here it's not,
在这里，它们大写，在这里不是，
and yet I bundle them together.
但是我把它们捆在一起。
I know my grammar, so I put periods
我知道我的语法，所以我把句号
at the end of the sentences, and yet they
在句子的结尾，但是他们
don't show up anywhere here.
不要出现在这里的任何地方。
So we got rid of the punctuation,
所以我们摆脱了标点符号，
and we made all words lowercase.
然后我们将所有单词都改为小写。
These are details, but they are details
这些是细节，但它们是细节
that you'll see in the code, so if you're
您将在代码中看到，所以如果您
wondering why, this is why.
想知道为什么，这就是为什么。
So step one, read the document, make it a list of words.
因此，第一步，阅读文档，将其制成单词列表。
Step two, compute the document vector.
第二步，计算文档向量。
Step three, take the two document vectors,
第三步，取两个文档向量，
and compute the angle.
并计算角度。
What is the angle of two document vectors?
两个文档向量的角度是多少？
Big ugly math formula.
大丑陋的数学公式。
The only thing that's relevant is that it takes these vectors
唯一相关的是它采用了这些向量
and computes an inner product.
并计算一个内积
So if we look at the code for angle vector, or vector angle,
因此，如果我们看一下角度矢量或矢量角度的代码，
you'll see that because numerator denominator lines two
您会看到，因为分子分母排成两行
and three, it calls inner product three times
第三，它调用内部产品三遍
and then it does some math with it.
然后用它做一些数学运算。
We don't care about the math.
我们不在乎数学。
We assume the math is order one.
我们假设数学是一阶。
We only care about inner product.
我们只关心内部产品。
How does inner product work?
内部产品如何运作？
Can anyone help me compute the inner product for these guys?
谁能帮我计算这些家伙的内积？
Yes?
是？
AUDIENCE: It's like the dot product?
听众：就像点积？
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: So, if we take the vectors and you multiply them,
听众：所以，如果我们取向量，然后乘以它们，
like, you're adding to the components, right?
例如，您要添加组件，对吗？
Because they're so thick--
因为它们太厚了-
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, this is too complicated, then.
维克多·科斯坦：好的，那太复杂了。
I'm seriously depressed, so give me
我很沮丧，所以给我
some clear instructions step by step.
一些明确的说明会逐步进行。
AUDIENCE: Like, I know you divide
听众：就像，我知道你分开了
by the length of each of the vectors--
通过每个向量的长度-
VICTOR COSTAN: Let's not worry about that.
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：不用担心。
I have these vectors, and I want an inner product.
我有这些向量，我想要一个内积。
I don't care about the angle, just the inner product.
我不在乎角度，只在乎内在的东西。
AUDIENCE: OK, well do 2 times 1 for the right.
听众：好的，做正确的2乘1。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So I take the here, shows up twice.
所以我在这里，出现了两次。
I take the here, shows up once.
我在这里，出现一次。
2 times 1, right?
1 2次吧？
AUDIENCE: Mhm.
听众：嗯。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
And then?
接着？
AUDIENCE: I would do the same for fox.
听众：我会为狐狸做同样的事情。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, fox shows up here once, shows up here once,
维克多·科斯坦：好吧，狐狸出现在这里一次，出现在这里一次，
so what I do?
那我该怎么办？
AUDIENCE: 1 times 1.
听众：1次1。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: And do the same for is.
听众：对is做同样的事情。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: And in should be 0.
听众：并且in应该为0。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] in.
观众：[听不清] in。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: And then outside would also be 0,
听众：那么外面也将是0，
and hat would also be 0.
帽子也将是0。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So it turns out you don't have to go through both lists.
因此，事实证明您不必同时浏览两个列表。
It's sufficient to go through one of the vectors
通过其中一个向量就足够了
and look up the words in the other vector.
并在另一个向量中查找单词。
Because if the words don't show up in any of the vectors,
因为如果单词没有出现在任何向量中，
their contribution is going to be 0.
他们的贡献将为0。
So my algorithm is go through each of the elements
所以我的算法是遍历每个元素
here, look up each of the words there, look up at the word
在这里，查找那里的每个单词，在单词中查找
here.
这里。
And if there's a word here and here,
如果这里和这里有一个字，
take out the number of times it shows up in each document,
拿走它出现在每个文档中的次数，
multiply them, and then add everything up.
将它们相乘，然后将所有内容相加。
So this is inner product.
因此，这是内部产品。
Everything else is good if you're writing a search engine
如果您正在编写搜索引擎，那么其他一切都很好
or if you're using the scenario application,
或者如果您正在使用场景应用程序，
but we're not really concerned with it.
但我们并不真正关心它。
OK, so now we have the three steps,
好的，现在我们执行三个步骤，
read the document, break it up into words,
阅读文档，将其分解为文字，
compute document vectors, compute our inner product.
计算文档向量，计算我们的内积。
So this is what we want to do.
这就是我们要做的。
And document distance 1 does it in a painfully slow way,
而文档距离1却以缓慢的速度完成了任务，
and we're probably not going to cover everything in recitation.
而且我们可能不会涵盖朗诵中的所有内容。
But if you go all the way up to document distance 1,
但是如果您一直到文档距离，
that's really, really fast.
那真的非常非常快。
It's 1,000 times faster.
快了1000倍。
So this is our job for the day.
所以这是我们今天的工作。
Let's look at the code.
让我们看一下代码。
Did anyone look at the code beforehand?
有人事先看过代码吗？
Nope.
不。
OK, so when I look at a big piece of code,
好的，所以当我看一大段代码时，
I like to look at it from top down.
我喜欢从上向下看。
So that means I start to the main function,
因此，这意味着我开始使用主要功能，
I see who is it calling, I see what everything
我看到它在叫谁，我看到了什么
is trying to do, and then I go into the sub functions
正在尝试做，然后我进入子功能
and recurves and basically do the same thing.
并进行反曲并基本上做同样的事情。
So I build a tree of who's calling what,
因此，我建立了一棵谁在说什么的树，
and that helps me figure out what's going on.
这可以帮助我弄清楚发生了什么。
So let's start with main.
因此，让我们从main开始。
And let's look at main.
让我们看一下main。
Lines 1 through 6 look at the arguments.
第1至6行着眼于参数。
We don't really care.
我们不在乎。
Line 7 and 8 call word frequencies for file.
第7行和第8行调用文件的单词频率。
I am abbreviating liberally.
我是自由的缩写。
And then line 9 calls vector angle.
然后第9行调用矢量角度。
So line 7 and 8 read the two documents,
因此，第7和8行读取了两个文档，
do steps one and two, and then 9 does step three.
执行步骤一和第二，然后执行步骤9和第三。
OK.
好。
Word frequencies for files.
文件的字频。
So the point of this is to read a file
所以这就是读取文件
and to produce a word document vector out of it.
并从中产生一个word文档向量。
And it does it in three steps.
它分三步完成。
Reads the file, line two.
读取文件，第二行。
Breaks up the file into words, so operation one,
将文件分解成单词，因此操作一，
this is line 3, and then line 4, it takes up the list of words
这是第3行，然后是第4行，它占用了单词列表
and computes a document vector out of it.
并据此计算出文档向量。
I don't care about reading files because I'll
我不在乎读取文件，因为我会
assume this is somehow done for me.
假设这是为我做的。
We care about the algorithms.
我们关心算法。
So as far as I'm concerned, this function
就我而言，这个功能
is calling get words from line list.
从行列表中调用获取单词。
Get words from line list, and count frequency.
从行列表中获取单词，并计算频率。
And if we skip all the way to vector angle--
如果我们一直跳到矢量角
we already talked a little bit about how all it does
我们已经讨论了所有功能
is it calls inner product three times
是三次调用内积吗
and then in does some fancy math of it.
然后对它做一些花哨的数学运算。
So this is how the code looks like big picture.
这就是代码看起来像大图片的样子。
OK, so to figure out the running time for main,
好，所以要弄清楚main的运行时间，
we need to figure out the running time for these two
我们需要弄清楚这两个的运行时间
functions and add them up, right?
功能并将它们加起来，对不对？
To figure out the running time for this,
为了弄清楚它的运行时间，
we need to figure out the running
我们需要弄清楚跑步
time for these functions and add them up, so on and so forth.
这些功能的时间，并将它们加起来，依此类推。
So as you go through each of the document distance versions,
因此，当您浏览每个文档距离版本时，
you want keep a scorecard of the implementation that shows you
您想要保留一个显示给您的实施计分卡
what the running time is, and this
运行时间是多少
helps you follow what was improved
帮助您遵循改进的地方
in each implementation.
在每个实现中。
So let's look at to get words from line lists.
因此，让我们看一下从行列表中获取单词。
What does it seem like its doing?
看起来好像在做什么？
Without reading the get words from string,
不读字符串获取单词，
can anyone tell me what it seems like it's doing?
谁能告诉我这是怎么回事？
If you just read lines 1 through 6.
如果您仅阅读第1至6行。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] through the list.
观众：[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So it's getting an input list.
因此，它正在获得一个输入列表。
And if you look at word frequencies for files
如果您查看文件的词频
at line 2, it names a variable line list.
在第2行，它命名了一个可变行列表。
So it seems like what's happening is,
看来发生了什么事，
reads a file into a list of lines.
将文件读入行列表。
And then that list of lines goes to get words from line lists.
然后，该行列表从行列表中获取单词。
So this is L in get words from line lists.
因此，这是从行列表中获取单词的L。
So it takes a list of lines which is the entire document,
因此，它需要一个包含整个文档的行列表，
and then?
接着？
AUDIENCE: Basically it removes the new lines.
听众：基本上，它将删除新行。
It sticks it into one giant list rather than a list of lines,
它会将其粘贴到一个巨型列表中，而不是一行中，
is that right?
那正确吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Almost, so you seem to get words from string.
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：几乎，所以您似乎从字符串中得到了一些单词。
Maybe we need to go through the function,
也许我们需要遍历该功能，
but do see the get words from string function name?
但是否看到从字符串函数名称获取单词？
So I will assume that it does something
所以我假设它会做某事
with each of the words.
每个单词。
And if the overall goal is to get a list of words,
如果总体目标是获取单词列表，
then I would assume that what that does is it takes a line
那么我认为那是要花一行
and it breaks it up into words.
并将其分解为文字。
Because this way, if you take up each line
因为这样，如果您占用每一行
and break it up into words, then when
并分解成文字，然后当
we put all the words together we get the words
我们把所有的词放在一起，我们得到的词
that make up the document.
组成文档。
Do people follow?
人们会跟随吗？
Any questions?
任何问题？
I like that people are nodding, by the way, keep doing that.
我喜欢人们在点头，顺便说一句。
That helps me go at the right speed.
那可以帮助我以正确的速度前进。
If you're not nodding, I'll keep explaining the same thing
如果您不点头，我将继续说明同一件事
over and over again.
一遍又一遍地。
OK, so get words from string.
OK，所以从字符串中获取单词。
Get words from string takes up a single line, that's a string,
从字符串中获取单词只占一行，这是一个字符串，
and produces a list of words.
并产生一个单词列表。
And we saw in the example there that it
我们在示例中看到了
has to take care of a few details such as making
必须照顾一些细节，例如制作
all the letters lowercase and ignoring
所有字母都小写而忽略
punctuation and skipping spaces.
标点符号和跳过空格。
So let's look at this code and figure out its running time.
因此，让我们看一下这段代码，弄清楚其运行时间。
And the way we're going to do that is we're
而我们要做的就是
going to look at each line, and we're
看每一行，我们
going to see what's the cost for that line
看看那条线的成本是多少
and how many times does it run.
以及它运行了多少次。
And once we have those two numbers,
一旦有了这两个数字，
we multiply them together and we see how much time
我们将它们相乘，我们会看到多少时间
does the program spend on that line in total.
程序总共在那条线上花费了多少。
So I'm going to write down line numbers here.
所以我要在这里写下行号。
9, 10, 11, 12, 13, 14, 15.
9、10、11、12、13、14、15
All the way to 23.
一直到23。
Too low.
太低。
20, 21, 22, 23.
20、21、22、23。
OK, so let's start with something easy,
好，让我们从简单的事情开始，
lines 9 and 10 How many times are they run?
第9和10行它们运行多少次？
AUDIENCE: Once.
听众：一次。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] Once in this method?
听众：[听不清]使用此方法一次？
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
So I'm only looking at this method.
所以我只看这种方法。
So assuming that the method gets one line, and the line has,
因此，假设该方法获得一行，并且该行具有，
I don't know, say, one line in characters,
我不知道一行字符，
and we need another variable which
我们需要另一个变量
we're going to figure out later.
我们待会儿找出来。
But for now, one line in characters.
但是现在，一行字符。
So how many times does line 9 run?
那么第9行运行了多少次？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Runs once.
运行一次。
How about line 10?
第10行怎么样？
AUDIENCE: Once.
听众：一次。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
What do they do?
他们在做什么？
Create new lists and assign them to variables.
创建新列表并将其分配给变量。
What's the cause for that?
是什么原因造成的？
AUDIENCE: Constant [INAUDIBLE]
听众：恒定[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Constant, excellent.
VICTOR COSTAN：持续不断，出色。
So I'll be skipping the order of so
所以我将跳过这样的顺序
that I don't have to write it 23 times.
我不必写23次。
So 1, 1.
所以1、1
OK, line 11.
OK，第11行。
It's iterates over all the characters in a line.
它遍历一行中的所有字符。
So how many times is it going to run?
那么它要运行多少次？
AUDIENCE: Like, the line?
听众：喜欢吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, which is?
维克多·科斯坦：好的，那是什么？
AUDIENCE: Line end characters.
听众：行尾字符。
VICTOR COSTAN: Awesome.
维克多·科斯坦：太棒了。
And just the fact of iterating takes constant time.
而实际上，迭代需要花费固定的时间。
I'm not sure we covered that.
我不确定我们是否涵盖了这一点。
So for each character, test if it's an alphanumeric character.
因此，对于每个字符，请测试它是否为字母数字字符。
Does anyone know what alphanumeric means?
有人知道字母数字是什么意思吗？
AUDIENCE: It's a letter and a number.
听众：这是一个字母和一个数字。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, so fancy word for letter or number,
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：好的，所以花哨的字母或数字，
A through Z, 0 through 9.
A到Z，0到9。
So how much time does it take to test
所以测试需要多少时间
if a character is alphanumeric?
如果字符是字母数字？
Guesses?
猜猜
AUDIENCE: Constant.
听众：不变。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, so constant time.
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，时间固定。
You compare it to the range A, Z and 0, 9.
您将其与范围A，Z和0、9进行比较。
How many times am I doing it?
我做了几次？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Thank you guys, this
VICTOR COSTAN：谢谢你们，这
is going much faster than the last recitation.
比上次朗诵要快得多。
You guys are active, I like it.
你们很活跃，我喜欢。
So, now for line 13.
因此，现在针对第13行。
That only gets executed when the character
只有当角色
is an alphanumeric character.
是字母数字字符。
So we're going to have to make some assumptions
所以我们将不得不做一些假设
about the document.
关于文件。
And to make my life easier, we're
为了让我的生活更轻松，我们
going to make the following assumption.
将做出以下假设。
If this is a natural language like, say, English,
如果这是自然语言，例如英语，
words are going to be a constant size, right?
单词将是恒定大小，对吗？
How many 500-character words do you see in English?
您用英语看到多少个500个字符的单词？
So let's say 5 to 10 characters per word.
假设每个字5到10个字符。
And since the difference is so small,
由于差异是如此之小，
I'm going to say all the words have the same size
我要说所有的单词都一样大小
W. And if you want to be more formal,
W.如果您想更正式一点，
you can replace word length with average length,
您可以将字长替换为平均长度，
and the math works out.
数学就算出来了
So each line has a number of words,
所以每一行都有很多字，
and the words are separated by exactly one space,
单词被一个空格隔开，
and the word has W characters.
这个词有W个字符。
So how many words do I have, by the way?
那么，我有几个字？
AUDIENCE: N divided by W.
听众：N除以W。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, good.
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，很好。
Someone's paying close attention.
有人在密切注意。
N divided by W plus 1.
N除以W加1。
And the reason that is, is a line
原因就是一条线
would look like this, word, space, word, space, word,
看起来像是单词，空格，单词，空格，单词，
space.
空间。
So W, characters, one space, W, characters, one space, W,
所以W，字符，一个空格，W，字符，一个空格，W，
characters, one space.
字符，一个空格。
That's why you have W plus 1 there.
这就是为什么那里有W加1的原因。
When we look at asymptotics it turns out
当我们看渐近线时，事实证明
that it doesn't really matter because W's a constant,
并不重要，因为W是一个常数，
W plus 1 is a constant, so order and words.
W加1是一个常数，因此顺序和单词。
But for now, let's keep track of W's to seem a bit more formal.
但是现在，让我们跟踪W似乎更为正式。
So line 13.
因此，第13行。
How many times is it going to run?
它要运行多少次？
AUDIENCE: W times 10 over W plus one.
听众：W乘以10乘以W加1。
VICTOR COSTAN: Excellent.
VICTOR COSTAN：太好了。
Let me pull them out.
让我把它们拔出来。
How much time does it take to run [INAUDIBLE].
运行[音频不清晰]需要多少时间。
AUDIENCE: Constant?
听众：持续吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Constant time, append,
VICTOR COSTAN：固定时间，追加，
covered in lecture, constant time.
讲课内容固定，时间固定。
So this is a bit tricky because if you have an array
所以这有点棘手，因为如果有数组
implementation that's naive, it's not constant time.
天真的实现，不是固定的时间。
But Python does some magic called table doubling, which
但是Python做了一些魔术，称为表加倍，
we'll cover later in the course.
我们将在本课程的后面介绍。
And this is why you can say that append takes constant time.
这就是为什么您可以说append需要固定时间的原因。
OK.
好。
Else, so if the character is not alphanumeric,
否则，如果字符不是字母数字，
than what's going on here?
比这里发生了什么？
Can anyone see what's happening there?
谁能看到那里发生了什么？
AUDIENCE: If its like, [INAUDIBLE].
听众：如果喜欢，[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, so let's say if it's a space.
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：好的，让我们说说它是否是一个空间。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah, this the harder part.
维克多·科斯坦：是的，这是最困难的部分。
I think you need to run this on an example
我认为您需要在一个例子上运行
to figure out what's going on.
弄清楚发生了什么。
I have to run it on an example in my head.
我必须在脑海中举一个例子。
So let's take this small example here, the fox is outside.
因此，让我们在这里举一个小例子，狐狸在外面。
And this is a single line, right?
这是一行，对吗？
Nice and handy.
很好，很方便。
So this can be the input for get words from string.
因此，这可以作为从字符串获取单词的输入。
And let's see what happens.
让我们看看会发生什么。
So first I start with word list which is empty list, character,
所以首先我从单词列表开始，它是空列表，字符，
lists, empty list.
列表，空列表。
Take the first character, it's alphanumeric,
以第一个字符为字母数字，
gets appended here, the second character, alphanumeric,
在此附加第二个字符字母数字，
appended here, third character, alphanumeric,
在此附加第三个字符，字母数字，
gets appended here.
被附加在这里。
Fourth character, not alphanumeric,
第四个字符，不是字母数字，
so I get to run lines 15 through 18.
所以我要运行第15至18行
OK, I did the easy part.
好吧，我做了简单的部分。
Someone walk me through the hard part.
有人带领我度过了艰难的时刻。
What happens in lines 15 through 18?
第15至18行会发生什么？
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: First, it takes that list and joins it
听众：首先，它接受该列表并将其加入
into a string. [INAUDIBLE]
变成一个字符串。 [听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, so this is a list of characters.
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，这是一个字符列表。
And join takes the list and makes a string out of it.
而join则获取列表并从中生成一个字符串。
So I'll have the string the.
这样我就得到了字符串。
OK, excellent.
好，很好
AUDIENCE: And it converts it all to lower case.
听众：并将其全部转换为小写。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: End up [INAUDIBLE] that to the word list.
听众：在单词列表中最后[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: The world list is up here, right?
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：世界名单就在这里，对吧？
So this is going to have the.
所以这将有。
AUDIENCE: And then it clears the character list, [INAUDIBLE].
听众：然后清除字符列表，[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So now as I go through the next word, I have F-O-X.
所以现在当我讲下一个单词时，我有FOX。
Then this becomes the word, and it gets added here.
然后，该词成为单词，并在此处添加。
So on and so forth for everything.
对所有事物等等。
Do people see how this method works now?
人们现在看到这种方法如何工作了吗？
I'm not getting that many nods, so questions.
我没有得到那么多的点头，所以提问。
If I don't get nods, I'll stop and you guys
如果我不点头，我会停下来，你们
have to ask what you're confused about.
不得不问你对什么感到困惑。
AUDIENCE: I think it's a little tricky because instead
听众：我认为这有点棘手，因为
of saying if it's not an alphanumeric character,
说如果它不是字母数字字符，
it's just like well, if the length of the list
如果列表的长度也一样
is greater than 0, which threw me off initially,
大于0，最初让我失望
but then I realized it was just, like, omission.
但后来我意识到这只是遗漏。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, so why does it do this?
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，那为什么要这样做呢？
What is the point of the length of the character list?
字符列表长度的意义是什么？
AUDIENCE: So that there are two spaces.
听众：所以有两个空格。
VICTOR COSTAN: Excellent.
VICTOR COSTAN：太好了。
So here I was nice and I had one space, one space, one space.
所以在这里我很高兴，我只有一个空间，一个空间，一个空间。
But if I'm sloppy when I'm typing and I have two spaces
但是如果我打字时马马虎虎，我有两个空格
here, then suppose this is space, space-- kind a small,
在这里，然后假设这是空间，空间-有点小，
but pretend.
但是假装
Go with me here.
和我一起去
So we got here.
所以我们到了。
We got the fox is.
我们得到了狐狸。
And then this list is empty because line 18 just
然后此列表为空，因为第18行只是
made it empty.
将其清空。
If I run the code the lines 15 through 18,
如果我在第15至18行运行代码，
it's going to add an empty word up here.
它会在这里添加一个空词。
And empty words aren't very useful.
空词不是很有用。
You'll see how many times the documents have
您会看到文件有多少次
too many spaces in them, so that doesn't really help.
它们中有太多的空间，所以这实际上没有帮助。
AUDIENCE: I mean, isn't that not an issue,
听众：我的意思是，这不是问题，
because you call if C is L1 before you actually
因为您在实际使用之前先呼叫C是否为L1
get to that.
做到这一点。
So you'd run through it again, but you would still
所以你会再次经历它，但是你仍然会
just skip over that.
跳过那件事。
That would fail, I mean it would not
那会失败，我的意思是不会
do anything for that equation.
为该方程式做任何事情。
VICTOR COSTAN: So first space.
维克多·科斯坦：那么第一个空间。
C as L now fails.
C作为L现在失败。
I run lines 15 through 18.
我运行第15至18行。
AUDIENCE: Yep.
听众：是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: Right?
维克多·科斯坦：对吗？
I have is here.
我在这里。
This becomes empty.
这变成空的。
AUDIENCE: Yep.
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Second space, C as L now fails again.
听众：第二空间，C为L现在再次失败。
AUDIENCE: Yep.
听众：是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: And if I wouldn't have the length check,
维克多·科斯坦：如果我没有长度检查，
it would run lines 15 through 18 again.
它将再次运行15至18行。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, so this is what it's trying to prevent.
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，这就是它要防止的事情。
So you can see that this code looks complicated, right?
这样您就可以看到该代码看起来很复杂，对吧？
It's trying to do a lot of things, it's complicated,
它正在尝试做很多事情，非常复杂，
it's hard to analyze.
很难分析。
Oh, well, let's go with it.
哦，好吧，让我们一起去吧。
Let's try to finish it up quickly.
让我们尝试快速完成它。
So now that we know what it does, let's
现在我们知道了它的作用，让我们
try to figure out how many times each line runs
尝试找出每行运行多少次
and what's the cost?
费用是多少？
Yes.
是。
AUDIENCE: So I think the total cost is N times 1
观众：所以我认为总费用是N乘以1
minus W over W plus 1.
减去W减去W加1。
VICTOR COSTAN: Wait, so here?
维克多·科斯坦：等一下，在这里吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, so you're saying N times 1 minus.
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，你是说N乘以1减。
OK.
好。
Why do you say that?
为什么这么说
I like it, but why?
我喜欢，但是为什么呢？
OK, it's because it's everything that is in the character,
好吧，这是因为角色中的一切，
and the line above it was characters--
上面的线是字符
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: --all alphanumeric, [INAUDIBLE]
听众：-所有字母数字，[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: So basically spaces, right?
VICTOR COSTAN：基本上是空格，对吗？
If we have word, space, word, space, word, space,
如果我们有单词，空格，单词，空格，单词，空格，
this happens for all the spaces.
所有的空间都会发生这种情况。
Cool.
凉。
So this is good.
所以这很好。
I'm going to make it a bit simpler.
我将使其变得更简单。
Same thing, it's just that it's slightly less intimidating.
同样的事情，只是它的威胁少了一点。
AUDIENCE: Oh, yeah.
听众：哦，是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: Cool, thank you.
维克多·科斯坦：太好了，谢谢。
Very brave, come up first.
非常勇敢，先出来。
What's the running time for line 14?
14号线的运行时间是多少？
So, cost for running it once.
因此，运行一次的成本。
AUDIENCE: Constant.
听众：不变。
Excellent.
优秀的。
VICTOR COSTAN: I like you guys.
维克多·科斯坦：我喜欢你们。
Nice.
真好
Line 15, how much time does it to take
第15行，需要多少时间
to take characters and put them into a list?
接受角色并将其放入列表？
AUDIENCE: N?
听众：不？
VICTOR COSTAN: N--
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：N--
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: --where N is the size of the list, right?
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：-其中N是列表的大小，对吗？
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So what's the size of the list now?
那么，列表的大小是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
OK, so when you're using more than one letter,
好，所以当您使用多个字母时，
the problem is you have to pay attention to which one
问题是你要注意哪一个
you're using.
您正在使用。
Because when we teach algorithms,
因为当我们教算法时
we say oh, this is N, this is N squared, so on and so forth.
我们说哦，这是N，这是N的平方，依此类推。
You have to replace it to the right letter.
您必须将其替换为正确的字母。
And I get confused about this all the time, so--
我一直对此感到困惑，所以-
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: --a serious problem.
维克多·科斯坦：-一个严重的问题。
AUDIENCE: --columns?
听众：-栏？
What are the two columns?
两列是什么？
VICTOR COSTAN: So this is the cost of running a line once,
维克多·科斯坦：这就是一次生产线的成本，
and this is how many times it's run.
这是运行了多少次。
AUDIENCE: Oh, OK.
听众：哦，好。
VICTOR COSTAN: Thanks for the question.
维克多·科斯坦：谢谢你的提问。
I should have said that in the beginning.
我应该在一开始就这么说。
Thank you.
谢谢。
OK, let's make this a little bit faster
好吧，让我们更快一点
and notice that lines 15 through 18
并注意第15至18行
all run the same number of times, right?
都运行相同的次数，对不对？
They're in the if, and there's nothing else
他们在如果，没有其他
that's changes the control flow there.
那改变了那里的控制流程。
So lines 15 through 18 are O and divided by W plus 1.
因此，第15至18行是O，然后除以W加1。
All right, line 16.
好的，第16行。
Take a word.
一句话
So take a string and make another string
因此，取一个字符串并制作另一个字符串
where each character is the lowercase version.
其中每个字符均为小写版本。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, cool.
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，很酷。
Why W, intuitively?
为什么是W，直觉上呢？
AUDIENCE: Because [INAUDIBLE] has to check to make sure
听众：因为[听不清]必须检查以确保
[INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah, so if you have a 10,000 character
维克多·科斯坦：是的，如果您的字符是10,000，
string you, have to go through 10,000 characters.
字符串，您必须输入10,000个字符。
Very good.
很好。
Append 917.
追加917。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Sweet.
维克多·科斯坦：甜。
And line 18, we said the character list of length list.
在第18行，我们说了长度列表的字符列表。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: [INAUDIBLE] OK, how many times
VICTOR COSTAN：[听不清]好，几次
do lines 19 through 23 run?
第19至23行运行吗？
AUDIENCE: Once.
听众：一次。
VICTOR COSTAN: At most, once.
维克多·科斯坦：最多一次。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Can anyone figure out what's the point of them?
维克多·科斯坦：有谁知道他们的意思？
AUDIENCE: Catch any trailing [INAUDIBLE]
听众：赶上任何尾随的[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Good.
维克多·科斯坦：好。
If you ended on the last letter of a word,
如果您以单词的最后一个字母结尾，
you want to make sure you catch that word.
您想确保您抓住了这个词。
VICTOR COSTAN: All right.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Very good.
VICTOR COSTAN：很好。
So I find it here.
所以我在这里找到它。
Then after I'm done with the loop at line 19
然后在完成第19行的循环之后
what the word list would have, the fox is.
单词表应该是什么，狐狸就是。
And then the character list would
然后字符列表将
have the characters for outside.
有外面的字符。
If I return the word list, woops, I just missed a word.
如果我返回单词列表，哇，我只是错过了一个单词。
So lines 20 through 22 are a copy of lines 15 through 17,
因此，第20至22行是第15至17行的副本
and they take care of the last word.
他们会处理最后一句话。
So line 19 is an if, and it takes the length of a list
所以第19行是if，它占用列表的长度
and compares it to the number.
并将其与数字进行比较。
What's the cost of that?
费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: Constant.
听众：不变。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, very good.
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，很好。
Checking list length in Python is constant time.
在Python中检查列表长度是固定时间。
We did that in lecture.
我们在演讲中做到了。
How about lines 20 through 22?
第20到22行如何？
I just gave it away, guys, come on.
伙计们，我只是把它给送了，来吧。
Someone--
有人-
AUDIENCE: The same as 15 through 17.
听众：与15到17相同。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, same as 15 through 17.
维克多·波士坦：好的，和15到17一样。
W, W, 1.
W，W，1。
Line 23, return constant time.
第23行，返回恒定时间。
OK, so now we know how much it takes to run a line once,
好，现在我们知道一次运行一条线需要多少钱，
how many times each line runs.
每行运行多少次。
So we're going to do a dot product of these guys.
因此，我们将为这些家伙做一个点积。
See, dot products are useful.
看，点积是有用的。
And if we do a dot product of these guys,
如果我们做这些家伙的点积，
we're going to get the total running time for the function.
我们将获得该函数的总运行时间。
So let's compute the partial terms.
因此，让我们计算局部项。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: I'm not going to write them down.
维克多·科斯坦：我不会写下来。
Let's just go through them and figure out what they are.
让我们通过它们来弄清楚它们是什么。
So you guys say them.
你们这么说。
AUDIENCE: 1, 1, N, N, weird equation--
观众：1、1，N，N，怪异的方程式
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, weird equation,
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，怪异的方程式，
what was the important part?
重要的部分是什么？
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[插入语音]
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah, the important part.
维克多·科斯坦：是的，很重要。
The important part is N, right?
重要的是N，对不对？
This is some constant times N, so N.
这是N的常数倍，所以N。
AUDIENCE: N, N, N, N, N, N, 1, 1.
观众：N，N，N，N，N，N，1、1。
VICTOR COSTAN: Pay attention.
维克多·科斯坦：注意。
AUDIENCE: 1, N.
听众：1，N。
VICTOR COSTAN: Pay attention.
维克多·科斯坦：注意。
It's not N, it's not 1.
不是N，不是1。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, actually is 1 I guess,
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，实际上我是1
if you think that W is a constant.
如果您认为W是一个常数。
Sorry.
抱歉。
AUDIENCE: You're testing us.
听众：您正在测试我们。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
1, 1.
1、1
VICTOR COSTAN: So I heard two numbers, N and 1, right?
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：我听到了两个数字N和1，对吗？
So this is 0 of N plus 1, which is order N,
所以这是N加1的0，即N阶，
because as N goes to infinity, 1 becomes really tiny.
因为当N达到无穷大时，1变得很小。
OK, so this is how you analyze a function.
好的，这就是分析函数的方式。
Big functions are horribly painful to analyze because you
大功能很难分析，因为您
have to look at each line and do this kind of reasoning.
必须查看每一行并进行这种推理。
And it's not even a top level function here,
而且这里甚至不是顶级功能，
so I don't even get to write anything here yet.
所以我什至没有写任何东西在这里。
So get words from string takes order and time
因此从字符串中获取单词需要顺序和时间
where N is the length of a line.
其中N是线的长度。
Let's look at get words from line list.
让我们看看从行列表中获取单词。
AUDIENCE: I have a question.
听众：我有一个问题。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yes.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
AUDIENCE: So [INAUDIBLE] is W characters long?
听众：那么[听不清] W个字符长吗？
Like, does it matter if the [INAUDIBLE]
就像，[音频不清晰]是否重要
VICTOR COSTAN: Does it matter--
COSTAN COSTAN：这有关系吗？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] make that assumption of that?
听众：[听不清]做出那个假设？
VICTOR COSTAN: So that I can reason for lines 15 and 16.
维克托·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：这样我就可以推断出第15和16行。
I can reason through them easily if I have a content length.
如果我有内容长度，我可以轻松地通过它们进行推理。
It turns out that if you have an average length,
事实证明，如果您有一个平均长度，
the results are going to be the same.
结果将是相同的。
Like overall, if you look at the running time as a sum of what's
与整体情况一样，如果您将运行时间作为总和
the running time for converting all the words to lowercase
将所有单词转换为小写的运行时间
and then appending them to the list.
然后将它们附加到列表中。
The sum of those is still going to be n N,
这些总和仍然是n N，
but that takes a bit more time to reason through
但这需要花费更多时间进行推理
so I took a shortcut.
所以我走了一条捷径。
Are you a math major, by the way?
你是数学专业吗？
You're very rigorous.
你很严谨
OK.
好。
So this is good, it's always good to try
所以这很好，尝试总是好的
to keep this in the back of your head
把它放在你的脑后
to make sure you don't fall for a trap.
确保您不会陷入陷阱。
So get words from string order N,
因此，从字符串顺序N中获取单词，
and we're trying to figure out get words from line list.
并且我们正在尝试从行列表中找出答案。
Any more questions before I do that?
在此之前还有其他问题吗？
Or does anyone want to tell me I'm wrong?
还是有人要告诉我我错了？
OK, good.
好好
So get words from line list.
因此，从行列表中获取单词。
Lines 2 through 6.
第2至6行。
2 3, 4, 5, 6.
2 3、4、5、6
Line 2.
第2行。
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, cost 1, how many times does it run?
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：好的，费用1，它运行了多少次？
AUDIENCE: Once.
听众：一次。
VICTOR COSTAN: Cool.
维克多·科斯坦：太好了。
Line 3.
第3行。
We need a new number, right?
我们需要一个新号码，对不对？
We need the number of lines in a document.
我们需要文档中的行数。
Let's say we have Z lines.
假设我们有Z条线。
So line 3 runs Z times, and 4 and 5 are in a loop
所以第3行运行Z次，而第4行和第5行循环
so they also run Z times What's the cost for line 4?
因此他们也要运行Z次4号线的成本是多少？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
VICTOR COSTAN: Excellent.
VICTOR COSTAN：太好了。
What's the cost for line 3?
第3行的费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: 1.
听众：1。
VICTOR COSTAN: 1.
维克多·科斯坦：1。
And what is the cost for line 5?
第5行的费用是多少？
AUDIENCE: Looks constant.
听众：看起来很稳定。
VICTOR COSTAN: Looks constant, OK.
VICTOR COSTAN：看起来很稳定，好的。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Does anyone else think it looks constant?
维克多·科斯坦：其他人认为它看起来很稳定吗？
Yeah.
是的
AUDIENCE: It's a trap.
听众：这是一个陷阱。
VICTOR COSTAN: It's a trap.
维克多·科斯坦：这是一个陷阱。
It's a trap.
这是一个陷阱。
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[插入语音]
AUDIENCE: --length of the two lists.
听众：-两个列表的长度。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Good.
好。
You paid attention in lecture, right?
你在讲课上注意了吧？
AUDIENCE: I try.
听众：我尝试。
VICTOR COSTAN: Nice.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
OK, so we have plus as an operator,
好，所以我们有加号作为运算符，
and suppose we work with two lists.
并假设我们使用两个列表。
The first list is 1, 2, 3, all the way through 1,000.
第一个列表是1，2，3，一直到1,000。
And the second list is 1, 2, 3.
第二个列表是1、2、3。
So when you code plus to combine them,
因此，当您编写代码并进行合并时，
if you say something like C equals A plus B,
如果您说C等于A加B，
you would expect that-- if this is A, by the way
您会期望-如果这是A，那么
and this is B-- you would expect that after you call this A is
这是B-您希望在调用此A后
still this, B is still this, and C
仍然是这个，B仍然是这个，C
is a list that contains everything.
是包含所有内容的列表。
So because of that, what plus has to do is make a new list,
因此，正因为如此，所以要做一个新列表，
append all the elements here, append all the elements here.
在此处附加所有元素，在此处附加所有元素。
So the cost of this if this list is 1,000 and this list is 3
因此，如果此列表为1,000，而此列表为3，则此成本
is 1,003.
是1,003。
Or if you have two lists of length, L1 and L2
或者，如果您有两个长度列表，L1和L2
the cost is order of L1 plus L2.
成本是L1加L2的阶数。
Now there's another Python method called extend,
现在有另一个Python方法叫做extend，
which does what I think you would expect plus
我想你会期待什么
to do in terms of efficiency.
在效率方面要做。
So what extend does is you call it a 1 or A on one list,
因此，扩展功能是在一个列表中将其称为1或A，
give it the other list, and it's going
给它另一个清单，它会
to take each element in the second list
采取第二个列表中的每个元素
and append it to the first list.
并将其附加到第一个列表。
So for each element here, it calls append on this list.
因此，对于这里的每个元素，它都会在此列表上调用append。
So what's the running time for extend?
那么延长运行时间是多少？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, there are too many directions and--
COSTAN COSTAN：好的，方向太多了，而且-
AUDIENCE: Length of the second list.
听众：第二个列表的长度。
VICTOR COSTAN: Length of the second list, excellent.
VICTOR COSTAN：第二名的长度，非常好。
So two lists, L1, L2, order of L2.
因此，有两个列表L1，L2和L2的顺序。
So it doesn't matter this is 1,000 elements
所以这没有关系1,000个元素
are a million elements, appending three elements is
是一百万个元素，附加三个元素是
going to take time proportional to three.
将花费与三成比例的时间。
OK now, let's see what's going on here.
现在，让我们看看这里发生了什么。
So we have Z lines and characters in a line.
因此，我们在一行中有Z行和字符。
I think I want a nicer constant.
我想我想要一个更好的常数。
No, let's go with this for now.
不，现在让我们开始吧。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] lines.
听众：[听不清]行。
VICTOR COSTAN: So this is the length of a word.
维克多·科斯坦：这就是一个字的长度。
Let's see, how many words will I have in a line?
让我们看看，一行中有多少个单词？
Let's say I have K words in a line, which is N divided by W.
假设我一行中有K个单词，即N除以W。
So I know that to get words from string
所以我知道从字符串中获取单词
returns a list of size K. So if that is the case, then
返回大小为K的列表。如果是这种情况，则
the first time line 5 runs, word list is empty.
第一次运行第5行时，单词列表为空。
And it's going to get K elements.
它将获得K个元素。
The second time it runs, word list has K elements
第二次运行时，单词列表包含K个元素
and gets K more.
得到K多
Third time, it has 2K elements, it gets K more.
第三次，它具有2K个元素，又增加了K个。
So the running time for this looks like this.
因此，其运行时间如下所示。
K plus 2K plus 3K plus 4K all the way
K加2K加3K加4K
until when I'm at the last line, if I have Z lines.
直到我在最后一行，如果我有Z行。
I had Z minus 1 times K elements in the list,
在列表中，我的Z减去K的1倍，
because I have Z minus 1 lines and I put all the words
因为我有Z减去1行，所以我把所有单词
in the list, and I'm adding K more words.
在列表中，我要再添加K个单词。
So total, Z times K running time.
因此，总计为Z乘以K运行时间。
So this is the total running time for this guy.
这就是这个人的总跑步时间。
And this is not constant, so it's complicated.
而且这不是恒定的，因此很复杂。
What is the sum come down to, asymptotically?
逐步得出的总和是多少？
AUDIENCE: Z plus 1K times Z over 2.
观众：Z加1K乘以Z乘以2。
VICTOR COSTAN: Ok.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Z plus 1K, ZK over 2.
Z加1K，ZK超过2。
Slow because I care about asymptotics,
慢点，因为我关心渐近线，
this is order of Z squared times K, right?
这是Z平方乘以K的顺序，对吗？
So now any one more natural number to work with
因此，现在可以使用任何自然数
would be the number of words in a document.
将是文档中的单词数。
And the number of words in a document
以及文件中的字数
is W, which is Z times K. So Z is W divided by K.
是W，是Z乘以K。因此Z是W除以K。
And if I substitute this, I get that this
如果我替代这个，我会得到这个
is equal to 0 of W squared over K. Now in a reasonable document
等于W乘以K的0的平方。现在在一个合理的文档中
that I see, there tends to be a limited number of words
我看到的是，字数往往有限
per line because the document has to fit on a page.
每行，因为文档必须适合页面。
So K's pretty much a constant.
因此，K几乎是一个常数。
So this comes down to order of W squared.
因此，这归结为W平方的阶数。
So if I go down here and look at get word from line list,
所以，如果我走到这里，看看从行列表中获取单词，
this is W squared, where W is how many words I
这是W的平方，其中W是我有多少个单词
have in a document.
在文件中。
How many of you guys are still with me?
你们中还有几个人呢？
Half.
半。
OK.
好。
Does anyone else want to ask questions,
还有其他人想问问题吗？
so that you can get back on track?
这样您才能回到正轨？
Yes, no?
是不是
AUDIENCE: It makes sense so far.
听众：到目前为止，这是有道理的。
VICTOR COSTAN: Thank you.
维克多·科斯坦：谢谢。
AUDIENCE: I think I didn't understand
听众：我想我听不懂
the part of [INAUDIBLE]
[听不清]的部分
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
Thank you.
谢谢。
So let's see what's going on lines 2 through 5.
因此，让我们看看第二行到第五行的情况。
So I have a word list, which at the beginning is empty.
所以我有一个单词列表，一开始是空的。
Then in line 4, words in line gets K words.
然后在第4行中，行中的单词得到K个单词。
And those K words in line five are added to word list.
并将第五行中的K个单词添加到单词列表中。
So after that, word list has K words.
因此，此后，单词列表包含K个单词。
Then I run through the loop again.
然后我再次遍历循环。
Get the words from string gives me K new words.
从字符串中获取单词给我K个新单词。
They get added to the list, which now has 2K words.
他们被添加到列表中，该列表现在有2K个单词。
Next time I get K more words, they
下次我再收到K个字时，他们
get that added to the list, which has 3K.
将其添加到具有3K的列表中。
So on and so forth until the end.
依此类推，直到最后。
I have ugly numbers.
我有丑陋的数字。
Z minus 1 times K words and I add the last K words.
Z减去K字乘以1，然后加上最后K个字。
I'm getting confused here.
我在这里很困惑。
And I get Z times K words.
我得到Z乘以K字。
So the word list is eventually going to have Z times K words,
因此，单词列表最终将具有Z乘以K个单词，
and it gets them K at a time.
然后一次得到他们K
The thing that does this addition is the plus operator.
进行加法的是加号运算符。
And the running time for the plus operator
而plus运算符的运行时间
is the size of the two lists, so it's this plus this.
是两个列表的大小，所以是这个加上这个。
So that's why the running time is first K, then 2K, then 3K,
这就是为什么运行时间首先是K，然后是2K，然后是3K，
then-- make sense now?
那么-现在有意义吗？
AUDIENCE: Yes.
听众：是的。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK.
维克多·科斯坦：好的。
So this is a subtle bug because if you change plus to extend,
因此，这是一个细微的错误，因为如果您更改加号来扩展，
you get [? bug ?] disk two, which runs a lot faster.
你得到 [？ bug？]磁盘二，运行速度快得多。
OK.
好。
So for everything else, we want to be
所以对于其他一切，我们都希望成为
able to do this sort of analysis,
能够进行这种分析，
but we want to do it faster.
但是我们想更快地做。
So you guys should look through [? bug list ?] one
因此，你们应该仔细检查[？错误列表？
through eight and do the same analysis for all the functions.
到八个，并对所有功能进行相同的分析。
And we're going to post recitation notes where
我们将在后面发布朗诵笔记
we tell you this is the function that changed,
我们告诉你这是改变的功能，
and this is the total running time.
这是总的运行时间。
And you should go through the lines
你应该仔细检查
and convince yourself that this is the right running time.
让自己相信这是正确的运行时间。
And you should do that until it becomes second nature,
而且，您应该这样做直到它成为第二天性，
because when you're writing Python code,
因为当您编写Python代码时，
you want to have this in your head.
你想把这个放在脑子里。
You don't want to have to write it down,
您不想写下来，
because if you have to write it down, you're going to be lazy
因为如果您必须将其写下来，您将变得懒惰
and you're not going to do it, and you're
而你不会这样做，而你
going to use plus instead of extend,
将使用加号而不是扩展号，
and your code is going to be horribly slow.
而且您的代码将非常缓慢。
So practice until this gets in your head,
所以练习，直到你意识到
and then you'll be able to see the running time for things
然后您将可以看到事物的运行时间
really quickly.
真的很快。
OK, do we have time for once more let me see.
好吧，我们是否有时间再让我看看。
OK.
好。
Let's look at the running time for inner products,
让我们看一下内部产品的运行时间，
because this is nice and easy.
因为这很容易。
2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
2、3、4、5、6、7
2 is 1, 1, very nice and easy.
2是1、1，非常好而且很容易。
3 looks at the first document list and iterates through it.
3查看第一个文档列表并对其进行迭代。
Iteration is constant time, but if the first document vector
迭代是恒定时间，但是如果第一个文档向量
has L1 elements, it's going to run L1 times.
具有L1个元素，它将运行L1次。
How about line 4, words 2 count 2 in L2.
第4行的单词2在L2中计数为2。
This is iteration again, so it's constant time to run it once,
这又是迭代，因此它是运行一次的恒定时间，
but how many times will it run?
但是它将运行多少次？
AUDIENCE: L2 times L1 times.
听众：L2倍L1倍。
VICTOR COSTAN: L2 times the 1, excellent.
VICTOR COSTAN：L2的1倍，出色。
So these two loops are nested inside each other
因此，这两个循环相互嵌套
so that means that lines 4 through 6
因此，这意味着第4至6行
are going to run once every time line 3 iterates.
每次第3行重复执行一次。
So sorry, actually line 4 is going
很抱歉，实际上第4行
to run once every time line 3 iterates.
每次第3行迭代一次运行一次。
And then everything inside the second 4
然后第二个4里面的所有东西
is going to run L1 times L2 times.
将要运行L1次L2次
So lines 5 and 6 are also going to run L1, L2 times.
因此，第5和第6行也将运行L1，L2次。
L1, L2, L1, L2.
L1，L2，L1，L2。
How much time does it take to do that if check there?
如果在那里检查需要多少时间？
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Why does it take a constant time?
VICTOR COSTAN：为什么要花固定的时间？
AUDIENCE: I was going to say, it wasn't constant,
听众：我要说的是，这不是一成不变的，
so you don't have to pair each character with no word.
因此，您无需将每个字符都与单词配对。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, good.
VICTOR COSTAN：好的，很好。
So we have two words, and equal, equal
所以我们有两个字，相等，相等
tells me are the words equal or not, right?
告诉我这两个词是否相等，对吗？
So the way you do that, is you have words like the and fox.
因此，执行此操作的方式是使用诸如and Fox之类的词。
You go through each character, and you
您经历了每个角色，然后
stop whenever you see different characters.
当您看到其他字符时停止播放。
But if you have something like, if you have a fake word
但是如果你有类似的话，如果你有假字
F-O-I and fox, then go through the first character,
FOI和Fox，然后经过第一个字符，
they're equal, second character, they're equal, third character,
他们是相等的，第二个字符，他们是相等的，第三个字符，
they're different.
他们是不同的。
So if you have length W words that
因此，如果您有W个字长
are different only in the last character,
仅在最后一个字符上有所不同，
this is going to be order W, right?
这将是订单W，对不对？
So the real--
所以真正的-
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: --yep, equals, equals 4 strings not constant.
VICTOR COSTAN：--yep，等于，等于4个不恒定的字符串。
It takes W time where W is the length of a word.
它花费W时间，其中W是单词的长度。
Now here we said that the length of a word
现在我们说一个字的长度
is constant because we're dealing with English.
是恒定的，因为我们正在处理英语。
So you could tell me it is constant because of that.
因此，您可以告诉我，它是恒定的。
But I would like to hear the argument before I take it.
但是，我想在接受之前先听听论点。
How about line 6?
第6行如何？
AUDIENCE: Well, if the plus equals
听众：好吧，如果加等于
is going to be the same thing before when we were,
那时我们将是同一回事，
every new time your plus equals, so it's
每一次新的加值等于
going to be like how the word list before we were adding it,
就像单词列表在我们添加之前一样，
where we have to create that object,
我们必须创建该对象的地方
and then add it to the length.
然后将其添加到长度。
I mean, its going to be length of sum.
我的意思是，这将是总和的长度。
Sorry.
抱歉。
And then you add in the new one.
然后添加新的。
So every time its going to be increasing, correct?
所以每次它会增加，对吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Almost.
维克多·科斯坦：差不多了。
It's a trap again.
这又是一个陷阱。
[INTERPOSING VOICES]
[插入语音]
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
Yeah, so this time they're not lists.
是的，所以这次他们不在列表中。
So if you look at what's going on inside there,
所以，如果您看看里面发生了什么，
you have count one and count two are
你数一，二是
these numbers in the document vector, so they're numbers.
这些数字在文档向量中，所以它们是数字。
And then some starts out at 0, and then it
然后一些从0开始，然后
keeps getting numbers.
不断获取数字。
So sum is going to be a number.
所以总和将是一个数字。
And multiplying numbers is constant time,
乘以数字是恒定时间
adding numbers is constant time, so plus for numbers
加数是固定时间，所以加数
is order 1 indeed.
确实是第1阶。
AUDIENCE: You're reassigning sum every time?
听众：您每次都在重新分配总和吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Which is also constant.
维克多·科斯坦：这也是不变的。
AUDIENCE: OK.
听众：好的。
VICTOR COSTAN: Because you're copying a number over.
维克多·科斯坦：因为您要复制一个号码。
So as long as you're copying one element over,
因此，只要您要复制一个元素，
that's constant time.
那是恒定的时间。
If you're adding two elements together-- two elements,
如果您将两个元素加在一起-两个元素，
not two lists-- that's constant time.
不是两个列表-这是固定时间。
So this is constant.
因此，这是恒定的。
And the last line is returned.
最后一行返回。
So what's the running time for this?
那么，这是什么时间？
AUDIENCE: L2 times L1.
听众：L2乘以L1。
VICTOR COSTAN: Excellent.
VICTOR COSTAN：太好了。
So I assume this is a constant.
所以我认为这是一个常数。
So this lets me say this is 1, and then
所以这可以说是1，然后
if we do the partial products we get 1L, 1L, 1, and L2.
如果我们做部分乘积，我们得到1L，1L，1和L2。
L1, L2, L1, L2.
L1，L2，L1，L2。
And if you add them up, you get L1 and L2.
如果将它们加起来，就会得到L1和L2。
So this is going to be L1, L2.
因此，这将是L1，L2。
Vector angle calls inner product three times, right?
向量角调用内积三次，对吗？
So what's it's running time?
那是什么时间？
AUDIENCE: L1, L2.
听众：L1，L2。
VICTOR COSTAN: Excellent.
VICTOR COSTAN：太好了。
Count frequency.
计数频率。
You're going to have to take my word for it
你将不得不相信我的话
that this is order of W squared.
这是W的平方的平方。
And if that's the case, what's the running
如果是这样，正在运行什么
time for a word frequency for file?
时间为文件的单词频率？
AUDIENCE: W squared?
听众：W平方？
VICTOR COSTAN: Cool.
维克多·科斯坦：太好了。
So.
所以。
What's the running time for main now?
现在main的运行时间是几点？
Last trick.
最后一招。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Yep, If you just add them up,
维克多·科斯坦：是的，如果您将它们加起来，
except there is one last trick there.
除了那里还有最后一招。
AUDIENCE: If W is constant, [INAUDIBLE]
听众：如果W为常数，则[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: No.
维克多·科斯坦：不。
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE] W's constant, right?
听众：[听不清] W不变，对吧？
VICTOR COSTAN: No.
维克多·科斯坦：不。
So W is the number of words in a document.
因此，W是文档中的单词数。
AUDIENCE: Oh.
听众：哦。
VICTOR COSTAN: So it's huge.
维克多·科斯坦：太好了。
If that's constant, then the whole problem
如果那是恒定的，那么整个问题
should run in order one time, and we're done.
应该运行一次，到此我们就完成了。
We're going home.
我们要回家了。
AUDIENCE: W squared because it beats out L1 and L2.
听众：W平方，因为它击败了L1和L2。
VICTOR COSTAN: OK, so--
维克多·科斯坦：好的，所以-
AUDIENCE: L1--
听众：L1--
VICTOR COSTAN: --you're going faster than me.
维克多·科斯坦：-你的速度比我快。
You're going too fast, but you're right.
你走得太快了，但是你是对的。
So word frequency for file is called twice.
因此，文件的字频称为两次。
The first document is going to have W1 words.
第一个文档将包含W1个单词。
The second document is going to have W2 words.
第二个文档将包含W2个单词。
So you can just copy W because this is called twice
所以您可以复制W，因为它被两次调用
for different files.
用于不同的文件。
So this is order of W1 squared plus W2
所以这是W1平方加W2的阶数
squared, different documents.
平方，不同的文件。
And then I have plus L1, L2.
然后我有加号L1，L2。
And you said that W1 and W2 dominate L1 and L2, right?
您说W1和W2支配L1和L2，对吗？
Because W's the total number of words in a document,
因为W是文档中单词的总数，
whereas L the is the number of unique words,
而L是唯一字的数量，
because it the length of the vector.
因为它是向量的长度
So that is true, but I'm not sure
没错，但我不确定
how to reduce this here to make use of that.
如何在这里减少它以利用它。
However, I made use of what you said already when I wrote this.
但是，当我写这篇文章时，我已经利用了你已经说过的话。
You see why?
你明白为什么吗？
Can anyone else see why?
谁能看到为什么？
So let's look at the vector angle again, lines 2 and 3.
因此，让我们再次看一下矢量角度，第2行和第3行。
So line 2, it calls inner product with L1 and L2.
因此，第2行使用L1和L2调用内部乘积。
But if you look at line 3, it calls inner product
但是，如果您看一下第3行，它称为内部乘积
with L1, L1 and then L2, L2 So the total running time
依次是L1，L1然后是L2，L2
for vector angle is actually L1, L2 plus L1
向量角实际上是L1，L2加L1
squared plus L2 squared.
平方加L2平方。
So if the first document has 1,000 words
因此，如果第一个文档有1,000个单词
and the second document as one word,
第二个文档是一个单词，
computing the inner product between L1 and L1
计算L1和L1之间的内积
is going to take a lot more time than computing
比计算要花很多时间
the inner product between L1 and L2.
L1和L2之间的内积。
So I can't leave out these terms.
所以我不能忘记这些条款。
They have to be here.
他们必须在这里。
However, when I add them up here--
但是，当我在此处添加它们时-
if I would write W1 squared plus W2 squared plus L1 squared
如果我写W1平方加W2平方加L1平方
plus L2 squared plus this-- in that case,
再加上L2的平方再加上-在这种情况下，
I can use the fact that W1 is bigger than L1,
我可以使用W1大于L1的事实，
and it cancels it out.
它取消了它。
Does this make sense?
这有意义吗？
Did I lose people?
我丢人了吗？
Ask questions, please.
请问问题。
AUDIENCE: But you can't get rid of L1 and L2
听众：但是你不能摆脱L1和L2
and not an [INAUDIBLE].
而不是[听不清]。
VICTOR COSTAN: You can't--
维克多·科斯坦：您不能-
AUDIENCE: [INAUDIBLE]
观众：[听不清]
VICTOR COSTAN: Oh, so I can't get rid of this term--
维克多·科斯坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：哦，所以我不能放弃这个名词-
AUDIENCE: --those, right?
听众：-对吧？
So this should be the sum of this and this, right?
所以这应该是这件事的总和，对吧？
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
VICTOR COSTAN: So it should be W1 squared plus W2 squared
维克多·波士坦（VICTOR COSTAN）：所以应该W1平方加W2平方
plus L1 squared plus L2 squared plus L1, L2.
加L1平方加L2平方加L1，L2。
AUDIENCE: Right.
听众：对。
L1 is strictly smaller than W1.
L1严格小于W1。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
听众：是的。
Goes away, L2 smaller than W2 goes away, and I get this.
消失，小于W2的L2消失，我明白了。
Correct.
正确。
So L1L2 isn't smaller than W [INAUDIBLE] squared?
那么L1L2不小于W [音频不清晰]的平方吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Is it?
维克多·科斯坦：是吗？
If you know more math than me, you
如果您比我了解更多数学
might be able to prove that it is,
也许可以证明它是，
but I don't, so I'm just leaving it in there.
但是我没有，所以我只是把它留在那里。
AUDIENCE: Ok.
听众：好的。
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah.
维克多·科斯坦：是的。
I think there is some relation, but I really
我认为有些关系，但是我真的
don't remember what it this, so let's
不记得这是什么了，所以让我们
leave it like that for now.
现在就这样离开。
Yeah, I think it should be the case that these
是的，我认为应该是这些
are bigger than this, but I'm not sure.
比这更大，但我不确定。
OK, yes.
好的。
AUDIENCE: How do you get the line for vector angle?
听众：如何获得矢量角线？
VICTOR COSTAN: How do I get the running time for it?
VICTOR COSTAN：如何获得运行时间？
So vector angle gets two vectors, right?
那么向量角得到两个向量，对吗？
The vector for document one and the vector for document two.
文档一的向量和文档二的向量。
The length of the first vector is L1.
第一个向量的长度为L1。
The length of the second vector is L2.
第二向量的长度为L2。
Now, line, where is it?
现在，行，在哪里？
Line 2, for numerator calls inner product with L1 and L2.
分子的第2行用L1和L2调用内积。
So we know that the running time is L1, L2 up here.
因此，我们知道运行时间在这里是L1，L2。
Now the next line, line 3 in vector angle,
现在是下一行，矢量角度的第3行，
calls inner product with L1 and L1.
用L1和L1调用内积。
So the running time is L1 times L1 which is L1 squared.
因此，运行时间是L1乘以L1的平方。
OK.
好。
AUDIENCE: Can we say that because there's
观众：我们可以这么说是因为
a bounded number of words in the English language, L1's bounded?
英语中有一定数量的单词，L1有界吗？
And as the length of the document
和作为文件的长度
gets really, really big, that [INAUDIBLE] constant?
这个[音频不清晰]常数变得非常非常大吗？
VICTOR COSTAN: Yeah, you might be able to do that.
COSTAN COSTAN：是的，您也许可以做到。
Yes, I think for the cases that we give you, that is true.
是的，我认为对于我们给您的情况，这是真的。
Yeah, I never thought of that, that's cool.
是的，我从没想过，这很酷。
AUDIENCE: It doesn't work if it's not a language, right?
听众：如果不是语言，那是行不通的，对吗？
If you just have gibberish?
如果你只是胡言乱语？
VICTOR COSTAN: Yes, also, to say that its constant is useful
VICTOR COSTAN：是的，也可以说其常数很有用
when the number of words in English
当英文单词数
is much smaller than your input size.
比您输入的尺寸小得多。
So if, say, English has 50,000 words
所以如果说英语有50,000个单词
and your input is 3,000 words, then the input is much smaller.
而您输入的是3,000个单词，则输入的内容要小得多。
But if you're input is a million words, which
但是如果您输入的是一百万个字，
I think is what we use, then yeah,
我认为这是我们使用的，是的，
it comes down to constant.
它归结为常数。
So yeah, that's a good insight.
是的，这是一个很好的见解。
That's really nice.
这是非常好的。
Anything else?
还要别的吗？
OK, so you get to go through document distance 3 to 8.
好的，因此您可以遍历3至8的文档距离。
We'll tell you what's changed, and we'll
我们会告诉您发生了什么变化，我们会
give you a chance to help you analyze it.
给您一个机会来帮助您进行分析。
But you have to analyze it, then update the scorecard
但是您必须分析它，然后更新记分卡
for each algorithm to see how things improve.
对于每种算法，看看情况如何改善。
Thanks.
谢谢。